spotxchange.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - SpotX

The SpotX Privacy Page is designed to share information with you about how SpotX processes data on behalf of our clients. We believe it is important to be as transparent as possible to remain a trusted partner in the ad tech ecosystem.

You may ask yourself, “Why are there so many ads on the internet?” Well, although it feels like it sometimes, the internet isn’t expressly ‘free’ – much of it is ad-supported. There are two primary business models that fund the majority of content on the internet: a subscription model and an ad-supported model. In a subscription model, you pay for everything you watch (e.g. Netflix). This works well in some environments, but would add up very quickly if the entire internet was funded this way. Instead, a majority of internet users prefer an ad-supported model, where audience members are served ads, and revenues from those advertisers are used to support the content.

#### For an example, click here to expand

Publishers create content to attract readers/viewers and then sell advertising on the basis of that readership/viewership to make money. When you are browsing an outdoor website, you may be identified as being “outdoorsy”. Later, when you are watching a video on the best 14er hikes in Colorado, you may see an ad from a leading retail brand touting its latest rugged jeans. The publisher uses a chunk of this advertising money to make more great content for you to read and watch. If they didn’t have a way to monetize their content, it would not exist or you would be charged for it. 

To create a positive user experience on ad-supported sites, online content, and apps that you use, publishers collect and SpotX processes some of your browser or device data.

## Applicability

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) applies to SpotX’s services and products. SpotX is the leading video ad serving platform providing media owners with monetization tools for desktop, mobile and connected devices. The platform features modern ad serving and programmatic infrastructure, and other monetization tools, like solutions for OTT and outstream video ad units. This policy explains what personal data we collect through our interactions, how we use the personal data, the reasons we share personal data and how you can access and control your personal data.

## What’s in it for you, the user?

GDPR and other privacy regulations empower users like you to control your data. There are a number of user experience and advertising quality benefits that come from data processing in the ad tech supply chain that benefit you directly. Our goal is to be as transparent as possible about what data we use and why.

### Get advertising that’s relevant to you

How many times have you gotten a diaper ad and thought “I don’t have kids! Stop trying to sell me this stuff!” – or an ad for steaks if you’re vegan, an ad for retirement living when you’re fresh out of college, or even an ad for a product that you already purchased? The list goes on, but everyone has a story of an ad that just felt irrelevant.

Accurate data allows ad tech companies and ultimately advertisers to provide **relevant advertising** to you at the time that you need it. Imagine you’re a new mom, with little time on your hands, and you get a coupon for diapers right when you need more. Awesome! Or you hear about a great new product that can help you make your life easier, more affordable, or more satisfying. Terrific!

In a 2015 Nielsen survey2 about new product discovery, 78% of respondents said they had discovered a new product from a TV or internet ad, compared to just 56% that found out from friends or family. On top of that, the number of people finding new products from news/lifestyle websites and social media increased by 15% between 2012 and 2015. Moreover, a recent study suggested 71% of consumers prefer ads tailored to their shopping habits3, so you’re not alone if you believe that advertising should be more relevant.

### Don’t suffer through the same ad 50 times

Have you seen the same ad multiple times in a day or week? You often end up quoting the commercial and feel a negative association with the advertised product. These duplicated ads are annoying and ineffective. Some of the data we collect helps us reduce the likelihood of this happening.

## Categories of information we collect about you

To accomplish the goals outlined above, SpotX needs to collect some information. However, rest assured that we will never know who you are. Rather, we collect information on the behavior that takes place on your device. There are different ways to capture user and device information, and they vary by device and environment. The information we collect or share also varies depending on the partner we are working with and why they might want to process the information. There are plenty of great resources available on the internet that describe these ID types, and we have outlined and defined a few below.

**Cookies 4 – Device: Desktop browsers such as Chrome, Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, and Safari, and mobile and tablet browsers to a lesser degree. **

You’ve probably heard the term cookie before in relation to internet browsing. Cookies are small pieces of information downloaded to your browser as you browse the internet. They act as a unique identifier for that browser (you will have a different cookie if you use Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox for example) and allow for many different types of activities. Because they are unique to the browser instance, if you change computers, clear your cookies5, or change browsers, the cookie will be different. This is in contrast to the device identifiers we outline later which are unique to each device, not each browser.

Cookies can help the browser or site owner:

  * Remember your site preferences such as your preferred language, currency, or content category
  * Maintain your shopping cart, and report activities within it (such as buying or abandonment)
  * Remember your password
  * Understand how you use the site (so that they can improve it)

For advertising, cookies help ad tech companies:

  * Know if you’ve watched or interacted with an ad
  * Understand your behavior as you move from site to site to help show you more relevant ads or to attribute a purchase to an ad that you saw
  * Sync audience data between buyers and sellers. In an ideal scenario, both buyers and sellers know that they’ve seen your device before and are able to apply the data they know about that ID to the ad opportunity. For example, a beverage company builds a profile based on your device’s behavior and believes that you are a “beverage intender”. As the Ad Server, SpotX needs to surface the information (such as the cookie) to the buyer to say “This ID is browsing on X site and is available to see an ad.” This enables the buyer to know that it is an opportunity they want to purchase and to do so. This process is called syncing. Cookies help facilitate this throughout the ad ecosystem. Syncing also helps achieve the benefits outlined in “What’s in it for you, the user”.

**Identify for Advertisers (IDFA) – Device: all iOS Devices**

  * IDFA is Apple iOS’s specific device ID for advertising. The IDFA is a random identifier assigned to an individual device, and is used to deliver customized ads. This ID is generated for mobile apps, whereas if you are browsing on a web browser via mobile device, a browser cookie will be used (see “Cookies”). The IDFA can be viewed or reset by the user.

**Google Play ID/GAID/AAID – Device: All Android Devices**

  * The AAID is Android’s version of the unique advertiser identifier with similar functionality and capabilities.

**SpotX Audience ID – Device: All connected devices**

  * The SpotX Audience ID is a unique ID that enables us to track audiences internally—it is derived from each ad call source, such as a cookie or IDFA. This ID is especially important for Do Not Track6 and Limit Ad Tracking7 requests. We use this ID to ensure we do not serve any targeted ads to you. It also can be used to help us limit the number of repetitive ads you might see.

**Publisher Provided ID (PPID) – Device: Depends, most connected devices**

  * A unique ID provided by the publisher / media owner to help track usage on their properties, usually through a login. Similar to the SpotX Audience ID, this ID enables the publishers to get a better picture of what types of users are visiting their sites and mobile or CTV apps. For example, a sports news site may create an PPID to help track interests, and activities across its properties to help create a better user experience and to help deliver more relevant advertising.

**IP Address – Device: All internet connected devices**

  * IP Addresses are a unique set of numbers such as 191.122.50.155 that identify the location of a device on a network. Similar to how a home address is used to send you mail, the IP address is a specific location that allows data to pass through the internet to another specific location. It is the basis by which a web page loads on your machine and not on someone else’s, for example. There are many different types of IP addresses that have varied uses in the modern web, though SpotX primarily uses IP address to identify general location (such as postal code, for localized advertising) and for cookieless environments (such as connected televisions). In many cases, we hash or obfuscate the IP address so that the usable information like general location is still passed but the exact IP is not.

## How we collate it together

After collecting some of the aforementioned data points, we collate the anonymous or pseudonymous information and pass it along to our partners. While you may view your experience online as a single, unified experience, the reality is that there are many companies doing work behind the scenes to create that experience for you. There is a whole ecosystem of publishers, advertisers, and tech companies, like SpotX, which help connect publishers with advertisers to create the free, ad-supported internet. By passing data between partners, we can help create a more unified experience online.

## Cross-Device advertising

Cross-Device advertising is a method in which a company attempts to group or map the devices that are owned by an individual or household. Cross-device advertising provides similar benefits as data collection (including relevant ads and frequency capping), but across your various devices. While SpotX can advertise to any IP connected device, we do not coordinate cross-device advertising.

#### For an example, click here to expand

You probably have a desktop, a mobile phone, a tablet, and maybe even a connected TV.  Cross-device techniques enable advertisers to deliver an ad campaign that is coordinated and designed for those specific devices.  For example, you might see an ad on a connected TV for diapers at night to generate brand awareness (when you are unlikely to go to a retail store and buy them).  You may then see a follow up ad for diapers on your phone when you are out and about during the day, this time with a discount attached. This technique enables an advertiser to tell a more complete and engaging story to the consumer in a way appropriate for the device, without being overwhelming or repetitive.  It also enables brands to understand the customer journey in a deeper way, which will help them generate a better customer experience for you.

## What we don’t know about you

Ok, so we’ve gone into a lot of detail about what types of information we collect and why. Here are some of the key data points that we don’t collect, but that you may be concerned about. Keep in mind that this is far from an exhaustive list. We make a conscious effort to never collect this information except from our own customers because, frankly, _we don’t need it and we don’t want it_.

Name  
Phone  
Address  
E-mail address  
Exact location  
Friends and family

## Our philosophy on data protection and what differentiates us

SpotX is run by people just like you. We browse the internet too, and want to be a part of a system that we all can trust. We read the same news articles, e.g. Facebook/Cambridge Analytica8, Equifax, Dun & Bradstreet, America’s JobLink9, and are genuinely concerned with some of the safety and transparency practices employed by other companies. This is why we believe in user privacy and rigorous data protection. One of the reasons we are so sensitive to this topic is because we have grown up in the ad tech industry and have seen the evolution of industry practices. This perspective allows us to be thoughtful in what we do; we believe we need to lead from the front and help push the industry toward better practices. As a leader in Brand Safety and with features like Audience Lock, we strive to remove bad actors from the system and to protect data from getting into the wrong hands.

From a technical perspective, we take precautions to minimize the risk of valuable personal data through techniques such as encryption, hashing, obfuscation, pseudonymization, and minimizing the duration that we hold onto data. We have also incorporated Privacy by Design and Default into our product development process so that privacy is considered from the very beginning of a new product idea.

Our data philosophy aligns well with the GDPR. We’ve written a series of blog posts on the topic and are looking forward to the positive changes it brings to the industry.

## CUSTOMER-PROVIDED INFORMATION

This section describes SpotX’s use of Personal Information and Anonymous Information that we collect when you or your representative use our Services. By visiting the SpotX website, located at http://www.SpotX.tv (the “Website”), and/or using our service (the Website and services we offer are collectively referred to as the “Services”), you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy.

### COLLECTION OF CUSTOMER-PROVIDED INFORMATION

The individuals who represent SpotX’s Customers or potential Customers may voluntarily provide their contact information and related data, including Personal Information, to SpotX by various means, including telephone, email, mail, the “Sign Up” button for Advertisers, the “Apply” button for Publishers, or other means. The Personal Information submitted to SpotX is used to communicate with and provide services for Customers. SpotX corrects or updates Personal Information when requested to do so by the applicable Business Contact.  
When a Business Contact accesses reports through SpotX’s servers, or otherwise uses the SpotX platform, certain information may also be collected passively, including your Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, and operation system. SpotX also stores a small text file called a cookie (“Cookie”) on your computer. Each Cookie has a unique identifier (“Cookie ID”) that enables us to recognize your login information and personalized settings. SpotX may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). SpotX also uses Cookies, and other navigational data that is passively collected, to gather information about your visit to the Services and the information which you searched and viewed on the Services. Most browsers are initially set up to accept Cookies, but you may reset your browser to refuse all Cookies or to indicate when a Cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Services may not function properly if your Cookies are disabled.

We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources, or from third-parties that provide services for us in connection with the Services. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you through our Services.

### USE OF CUSTOMER-PROVIDED INFORMATION

In general, Personal Information you submit to us is used by us either to register you for our Services, respond to requests that you make, communicate with the Customer for whom you work regarding the Services (including for invoicing purposes), to improve our Services and to better tailor the features, performance and support of the Services, and to offer you additional information, opportunities, and functionality. If you provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the Personal Information in it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
We may provide Personal Information to third-parties to the extent such third-parties provide operational assistance (i.e., outsourced or third-party services) to SpotX and then only for that purpose. Examples of such third-party services include sending email, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. However, these service providers do not have any independent right to share this information (except pursuant to a legal requirement such as a subpoena or warrant). SpotX may share some or all of your Personal Information with current or future Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.  
SpotX may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns so that we may enhance our Services. We reserve the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information to third-parties in our discretion. This Anonymous Information may include, but is not limited to, browser type, URLs visited, and search terms entered.

SpotX does not “sell” the information we collect through the use of our services as defined under CCPA.

**We use cookies to track site performance on our Website**

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources, so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies, we will not know when you have visited our site.

## What is the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)?

GDPR is a set of rules in the European Union designed to give residents of the EU more control over their Personal Data. It’s goal is to ensure that citizens and businesses in the European Union can fully benefit from the modern digital economy. According to the text, the “Regulation protects fundamental rights and freedoms of natural persons and in particular their right to the protection of personal data.” Generally, it applies to the Personal Data of EU residents and the companies that handle it. Refer to articles 1-3 of the GDPR to determine whether it applies to you.

## Your rights under GDPR

If GDPR applies to you, you can find the [complete](https://gdpr-info.eu/chapter-3/) list of data subject rights in Chapter 3 of the GDPR, or click below for a summary:

  1. **Right of Access** – You have the right to obtain information from the controller or processor (us) such as the purposes of processing, categories of personal data concerned, recipients of the data, how long it may be stored, and notification of the remaining rights outlined here.
  2. **Right to Rectification** – The right to rectification concerns the ability to correct any inaccurate data concerning the data subject. The data that we collect, such as your IP Address, is not technically correctable, so we request that you exercise your right to erasure instead.
  3. **Right to Erasure** – This is also known as the right to be forgotten. If you request to be forgotten, your old ID will be disassociated from you and any information we have on that ID will be deleted in 14 days.
  4. **Right to Data Portability** – You have the right to receive any personal data we have in a commonly used and machine-readable format, though we are unaware of any other services which could utilize the information productively.

## What is the California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA)?

The purpose is to expand existing privacy rights in California, to help [Californian consumers] “Own Your Personal Information, Control Your Personal Information, Secure Your Personal Information” and “Hold Big Corporations Accountable” (CA Privacy). According to the California Consumer Privacy Act website, the law gives Californians the following rights:

Right to know all data collected by a business on you, twice a year, free of charge.

Right to say no to the sale of your information.

Information Security: Right to sue companies who collected your data, where that data was stolen or disclosed pursuant to an unauthorized data breach, if the company was careless or negligent about how it protected your data (i.e. if the data was unencrypted, un-redacted, or the company didn’t have reasonable security policies and procedures in place to protect it).

Right to delete data you have posted.

Right not to be discriminated against if you tell a company not to sell your personal information.

Right to be informed of what categories of data will be collected about you prior to its collection/at point of collection, and to be informed of any changes to this collection.

Mandated opt-in before sale of children’s information (under the age of 16).

Right to know the categories of third parties with whom your data is shared

Right to know the categories of sources of information from whom your data was acquired.

Right to know the business or commercial purpose of collecting your information.

This privacy policy contains all the information you need to exercise your rights under CCPA including the Right to know data collected about you and the Right to say no to the sale of personal information.

SpotX Sale of Data under CCPA

SpotX’s use of the personal information specified in the Categories of Personal Information, Data Retention, and General Workflow sections of this privacy policy may qualify as a “Sale” under CCPA, since the data we provide to partners helps us generate valuable consideration. It is likely that each of these categories was “sold” in the past twelve months.

## General Workflow – Sources of Personal Information

The following describes the general workflow of data in our systems.

  * The key workflow is triggered by a user (Data Subject), who is visiting the publisher’s (Controller’s/Business’s) Website and/or Application by requesting the website URL through the browser or by opening the Application on the applicable device.
  * Within the Website and/or Application an ad tag is integrated, which triggers a request to the SpotX ad serving Platform, requesting an advertisement.
  * In the event that the publisher has a 1st party data connection through the SpotX platform, SpotX will cross reference the request with the Data Management Platform (Sub-processor/Service Provider) used by the Publisher.
  * SpotX cooperates with different 3rd Parties (Sub-processors/Service Provider), including but not limited to DSP’s – to enable and allow monetization of the publisher’s Website and/or Application.
  * With every creative delivered by SpotX, it will trigger requests to 3rd party brand safety measurement vendors (Sub-processors/Service Provider), which are measuring the compliance of the website and the creative displayed with the expectations of the advertisers.
  * Furthermore, SpotX synchronizes user ID’s with the 3rd Party Data Management platforms and DSP’s for the purpose laid out in Data Retention Policies
  * After the ad delivery process, SpotX aggregates the number of delivered creatives and standard KPIs including but not limited to: Clicks and Completed views. This information is used to invoice the 3rd Parties used for monetization, be it by the publisher or SpotX. Additionally this information is used to execute the business agreement between the publisher and SpotX.

## Technical and operational measures

The following describes the technical and operational measures that SpotX uses to ensure we follow applicable Data Protection Laws.

**Physical Access Control**

The aim of physical access control is to prevent access by unauthorized persons to data processing facilities which are used for the processing or use of personal data.

SpotX maintains its own cages within data centers, which are located in Virginia, Denver, Amsterdam and Singapore. All entrants to the data center are required to to identify themselves, typically biometrically, as well as show proof of identity to on-site security operations. Only authorized employees, contractors and visitors are allowed entry to the data centers. Visitors must register in advance to visit the data center, and must specify the areas they wish to visit within. When visitors arrive, their identity and approval to visit the site is verified by on-site operations. Specific cages are secured by badge and key access and have 24/7 CCTV monitoring. Access to the SpotX cage can only be given by employees and maintenance, when the visit has been requested and authorized by data center and SpotX systems management.

**System Access Control**

The objective of system access control is to prevent unauthorized persons from using data processing facilities used for the processing or use of personal data.

SpotX has multiple measures in place to ensure no unauthorized individuals can access the SpotX systems. These measures include but are not limited to:

  * SpotX offices have secured entry using badges and keys
  * Access to systems is provided based on a personal log in that has to meet strict requirements and is exposed to either 2-step verification and/or placed behind a secured VPN.
  * Every employee is assigned a role which places the employee in particular user groups, these groups determine to which systems and to which level the employee has access with a personal log in.
  * Provided workstations and mobile computers are equipped with software that allows instant close off and wiping of the the device in question should such equipment be compromised.

**Data Access Control**

The following measures are used to ensure that those authorized to use a data processing system can only access data in accordance with their access permission, and that personal data cannot be read, copied, changed or deleted during processing and use and after storage without authorization:

  * As stated in the systems control section of this appendix, access levels are assigned to groups of employees, or individuals, at SpotX based on role and responsibility.
  * Only authorized system operators have access to production data.
  * SpotX has a strict policy in place to make sure all access is revoked upon termination of employment.
  * Data made available outside the authorized system operator’s access level is hashed and salted.

**Separation Control**

The goal of separation control is to ensure that data collected for different purposes is processed separately.

Within SpotX all the personal data that is being processed is kept in a separate database cluster. Only authorized system operators have the ability to access the production data, all developers only have the ability to develop on staging data.

Every developer has personalized and logged access to the code repositories. All development goes through extensive code review. After review it is tested in our test environment.

Deployments to production are strictly managed by our Project Management team and can only be made by authorized system operators that are organizationally separate from the development team. Every deployment on production must be approved and documented via a central ticketing system with role separation.

**Transfer Control**

The aim of transfer control is to ensure that personal data cannot be read, copied, modified or removed by unauthorized parties during the electronic transmission of these data or during their transport or storage on a data carrier. It must be possible to verify and identify where a transmission of personal data by entities for data transmission purposes takes place.

In the process of transferring information – SpotX only stores Personal Data of EU citizens in its Amsterdam data center. All Personal Data that gets transferred from our Amsterdam data center to our data centers located in the United States is hashed and salted before transfer. Transfer takes place on an isolated connection specific to SpotX. For these transfers our required model clauses are in place.

SpotX logs all received and transferred bodies for both internal and external transport of data. SpotX aims to have the transport take place on secured endpoints.

**Input Control**

By using the following measures, SpotX ensures the exact circumstances for data input, which can be checked and identified afterwards:

  * The SpotX platform historicizes any changes to the system settings made on an individual user basis.
  * Input processes are exposed to a strict integration and input process.
  * All input is logged and can be traced.

**Availability Control**

SpotX has multiple measures in place to ensure availability and resilience of data.

  * All data centers containing SpotX’s data cages are equipped with alarms on server rooms, temperature and humidity monitors, are connected to emergency generators, are connected to overvoltage protection devices and smoke and fire alarms.
  * SpotX has 24/7 monitoring in place that checks the operational parameters of the hardware and is connected to a pager system that warns our dedicated system engineers in case of alarms.
  * Additionally, all SpotX data is part of a clear stated backup plan and part of a disaster recovery plan.

**Job Control**

All third parties that process Personal Data are subject to a Data Processing Agreement. Every new partner relationship that is established will be part of a diligence process and will be subject to the Data Processing Agreement. SpotX has safeguards in place that will prevent EU traffic from being processed by any party without a Data Processing Agreement in place.

All Data Processing Agreements have language ensuring alignment with the requirements set by GDPR including but not limited to rights of audit, destruction of data upon termination of contract and documentation of security measures in place set by the 3rd Party.

## Data retention policies

See below for more specifics on the data we collect and how long we keep it.

**Personal Data** | **Cookie_id (user_id)** | **Device IDs** | **IP Address**  
---|---|---|---  
**Means of Collection** | This is a randomly generated, unique, alphanumeric text string (identifier) set by placing a cookie in the browser. No further information about the user is stored on this identifier. The collection of the cookie_id information can be done in 3 ways. 

  1. Reading existing SpotX cookie in the browser
  2. Random generation upon placing of cookie – if none is detected
  3. Received by the Controller upon ad call

| Device IDs are not actively collected and are only used when proactively transferred by the Controller in the Call to SpotX. | The IP Address can be collected by SpotX in 2 ways: 

  1. When the call to SpotX is made by the Controller in the browser. SpotX will use the browser header to obtain the IP Address
  2. When the call to SpotX is not made in the browser, the Controller proactively transfers the IP address in the call itself.

**Means of Processing** | The cookie_id is used to identify campaigns eligible for delivery | The Device ID is used to identify campaigns eligible for delivery | The IP Address is used to identify campaigns eligible for delivery 

The IP Address is cross checked with databases to determine Geographic Location and ‘Real World’ Person validation.  
  
**Means of Sharing** | The cookie_id can not be accessed by other parties. It can be transmitted to Sub-processors in 3 ways: 

  1. Upon request for ad delivery; if no buyer_id (the cookie_id of the DSP’s) is available, the cookie_id will be transmitted.
  2. Forwarding to Sub-processor by means of Macro in VAST call
  3. In the synchronization call to the Sub-processors (DSP’s)

| The Device ID can be transmitted to Sub-processors in 2 ways: 

  1. Upon request for ad delivery, by the DSP, the device_id will be transmitted
  2. Forwarding to subprocessors by means of Macro in VAST call

| The IP address can be transmitted to Sub-processors in 3 ways: 

  1. Upon request for ad delivery, by the DSP, the IP address will be transmitted
  2. Forwarding to Sub-processors by means of Macro in VAST call
  3. Request send to Brand Verification tools with the sole aim of fraud detection

**Means of Storing** | The cookie_id is stored on servers associate with the Audience Management Engine (AME) – separately from all other non-PII data points. | The Device ID is stored hashed and salted onto our data servers and is irreversibly anonymized | The IP Address is stored hashed and salted and is irreversibly anonymized  
**Place of Processing** | SpotX owned Amsterdam Data center for EU data and Denver or Virginia data center for California data | SpotX owned Amsterdam Data center for EU data and Denver or Virginia data center for California data | SpotX owned Amsterdam Data center for EU data and Denver or Virginia data center for California data  
**Place of Storage** | SpotX owned Amsterdam Data center for EU data and Denver or Virginia data center for California data | SpotX owned Denver or Virginia Data center | SpotX owned Denver or Virginia Data center  
**Retention Period of Storage** | 14 days in EU, 30 days outside EU | 18 months | 18 months  
**Purpose** | The purposes of the cookie_id is: 

  1. In order to prevent over exposure of a particular campaign to the Data Subject, SpotX and the respective DSP perform frequency capping. The cookie_id is technically required for this purpose.
  2. Allows for matching of the cookie_id to enable the Sub-processors’ purposes of processing, including and not limited to Frequency capping.
  3. To enable audience-based targeting, including activation of Publisher and Advertiser first-party data and DMP third-party data “reselling.” Advertiser first-party data is owned by the advertiser and may be executed under advertiser instructions (with permission of Publisher)

| The purpose of the Device ID is: 

  1. In order to prevent over exposure of a particular campaign to the Data Subject, SpotX and the respective DSP perform frequency capping. The device id is technically required for this purpose, in case of cookieless environment.
  2. To enable audience-based targeting, including activation of Publisher and Advertiser first-party data and DMP third-party data “reselling.” Advertiser first-party data is owned by the advertiser and may be executed under advertiser instructions (with permission of Publisher)

| The purpose of the IP Address is: 

  1. In order to delivery a campaign coming from the relevant country and in the relevant language to the Data Subject, SpotX uses the IP Address to determine the Data Subjects Geographic location.
  2. In order to protect the advertisers for campaign delivery on ‘non human’ traffic, SpotX uses the IP Address to perform fraud detection and prevention.
  3. SpotX uses the IP Address periodically to conduct technical troubleshooting
  4. To enable audience-based targeting, including activation of Publisher and Advertiser first-party data and DMP third-party data “reselling.” Advertiser first-party data is owned by the advertiser and may be executed under advertiser instructions (with permission of Publisher)

**Legal Basis – Art 6 of GDPR** | The cookie_id can be legitimately processed by:  
-> Active Opt in (Art. 6(A))  
-> Legitimate Interest (Art. 6(F)) | The Device ID can be legitimately processed by: 

-> Active Opt in (Art. 6(A))

-> Legitimate Interest (Art. 6(F))

| The IP Address will be processed on: 

-> Legitimate Interest (Art. 6(F))  
  
## Security breach notification

**_Incident Management_**. If SpotX becomes aware of any accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure of, or access to any Personal Data transmitted, stored or otherwise Processed on SpotX’s equipment or in SpotX’s facilities, SpotX will: (i) notify our Publishers of the Security Breach without undue delay (ii) investigate the Security Breach and provide Publisher with all relevant information about the Security Breach; and (iii) take all steps to mitigate the effects and to minimize any damage resulting from the Security Breach. SpotX documents its Security Breach Management Plan, which Publisher may review subject to confidentiality considerations.

## Age Limitations

To the extent prohibited by applicable law, SpotX does not allow use of our Services and Websites by anyone younger than 16 years old. If you learn that anyone younger than 16 has unlawfully provided us with Personal Data, please contact us and we will takes steps to delete such information.

## List of sub-processors under GDPR

Expand to see the full list of sub-processors that SpotX utilizes to deliver our Services.

**Demand Side Platforms**

4info  
Active Agent  
Acuity  
Addictive Mobility  
Adelphic  
Adgear  
Adobe  
AdTheorent  
Adscience  
Appier  
Beeswax  
Bidswitch  
Bidtheatre  
BrightRoll DSP by Yahoo  
Centro  
DataXu

Delta Projects  
Drawbridge  
Dynadmic  
Electric Ads  
Emerse  
Eq Works  
EyeReturn  
Eyeview  
Go2Mobi  
GumGum  
iotec  
LoopMe  
MaxPoint  
Mobpro  
OpenX  
Project Summer  
PulsePoint  
Simpli.fi

Sizmek  
Smadex  
smartclip  
Somo Audience Corp  
Splicky  
SundaySky  
Tabmo Hawk DSP  
Tremor / VideoHub  
Tru Optik  
VideoHub  
VideoAmp  
Videology  
ViralGains  
Visible Measures  
YuMe DSP  
ZypMedia

**Data Management Platforms**

Lotame  
Krux  
LiveRamp  
Roku  
Microsoft  
Google  
Nielsen/Exelate  
TruOptik

Neustar  
Adobe  
Nugg.ad  
BlueKai

**Other Sub-Processors**

ComScore  
Moat

## Notice about controllers under GDPR

To become GDPR compliant, SpotX signed a data processing agreement (DPA) with our Publishers to define our rights and responsibilities regarding Personal Data protection in the EU. This agreement listed a number of Demand Side Platforms (DSPs) as sub-processors of SpotX. In our discussions to secure DPAs between SpotX and the DSPs, some DSPs indicated that due to the nature of their processing activities, they consider themselves as data Controllers. As a result, we’ve agreed to implement data transfer agreements with these particular DSPs to properly protect and process the Data in a manner that meets the requirements of applicable Data Protection Laws. Please note that many of these DSPs have committed to adopt the IAB Transparency and Consent Framework. With this market-wide standard, there will be a common code of conduct throughout the industry with regards to data transfer and protection.

As independent Controllers, these DSPs will not be bound by processing instructions from other parties. If you do not wish for us to share Personal Data with these DSPs on your behalf, including Data to enable monetization and audience syncing, please contact your account team and they can help you block the DSP globally or regionally.

Below you will find a list of all parties previously referenced as sub-Processors under our DPA. These DSPs have now defined themselves as Controllers. For more information on their data practices, please refer to their privacy policies. This list will be kept up to date here:

AppNexus  
A9 Amazon  
Adform  
ActiveAgent  
Conversant DSP  
The Trade Desk  
DBM  
Amobee (f.k.a. Turn)  
RhythmOne/Blinkx  
AOL One  
RUN DSP  
MediaMath  
Quantcast

## Contact Information

For privacy related questions or inquiries, email [privacy@spotx.tv](mailto:privacy@spotx.tv).

**SpotX Data Protection Officer**  
**Name:** ePrivacy GmbH  
represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer  
Große Bleichen 21  
20354 Hamburg, Germany  
**Email:** [info@eprivacy.eu](mailto:info@eprivacy.eu)

## GENERAL PROVISIONS

### SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY

SpotX has put in place commercially reasonable technical and operational safeguards to secure the information we collect online. However, no company, including SpotX, can fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

We may disclose Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the visitors and users of our Services, or third parties.

### CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make material changes to it we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the Website, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what Personal Information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

## Please visit the links below to exercise your rights with SpotX data including “do not sell.”

This privacy policy was last updated on December 18, 2019.

1 Yukhanaov, Anna. “Consumers Love to Hate Ads but Won’t Pay to Escape Them.” Morning Consult, 24 Sept. 2017, morningconsult.com/2017/09/23/consumers-love-hate-ads-wont-pay-escape/.  
2 “Looking to Achieve New Product Success? Listen to Your Customers. .” Nielsen.com, www.nielsen.com/content/dam/nielsenglobal/dk/docs/Nielsen%20Global%20New%20Product%20Innovation%20Report%20June%202015.pdf.  
3 Kirkpatrick, David. “Study: 71% of Consumers Prefer Personalized Ads.” Marketing Dive, 9 May 2016, www.marketingdive.com/news/study-71-of-consumers-prefer-personalized-ads/418831/.  
4 Geary, Joanna. “Tracking the Trackers: Introduction to Cookies and Web Tracking.” The Guardian, Guardian News and Media, 23 Apr. 2012, www.theguardian.com/technology/2012/apr/23/cookies-and-web-tracking-intro.  
5 “Clear Your Web Browser’s Cache, Cookies, and History.” Indiana University Knowledge Base, 14 May 2018, kb.iu.edu/d/ahic.  
6 “All About DNT.” All About DNT, Future of Privacy Forum, allaboutdnt.com/.  
7 “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads in the App Store and Apple News.” Apple Support, Apple, Inc., 3 Jan. 2018, support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074.  
8 Kleinman, Zoe. “Cambridge Analytica: The Story so Far.” BBC News, BBC, 21 Mar. 2018, www.bbc.com/news/technology-43465968.  
9 Datch, Heidi. “2017 Data Breaches – The Worst Breaches, So Far | IdentityForce®.” Identity Force, 1 May 2018, www.identityforce.com/blog/2017-data-breaches.
